[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
tricentis tasa Advanced Training as you
all know I already published 50 YouTube
videos covering beginners intermediate
and advanced level Concepts from past
couple of videos onwards have started
teaching you the realtime scenarios
where you might encounter with different
types of obstacles and how can we solve
those obstacles while automating your
test cases by using tricentis
tosa so I have already published eight
realtime scenarios explaining the
resolution for eight different types of
obstacles this is our lesson 9 in terms
of real time scenarios and this is our
lesson 51 in terms of overall tric tasa
training please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a real time
scenario where you need to interact with
web
tables and you need to drag and drop the
rows from the web table to the new empty
web table so basically the rows within
the web table are Dynamic and you need
to drag those
rows in sequence order to the new empty
table so this is the obstacle we are
going to solve so let us first see and
understand in detail what is the
obstacle we are solving
for so this is our obstacle to-do list
this is categorized as medium but I can
say it has hard okay so now let us go
for
it so if you see here so move all tasks
from to do to
completed in the order of their given
task
ID so which means I have to drag the
row from this
table and drop here but while dragging I
need to make sure that I drag in
sequence order one this first row is
first and then row with id2 is second
and row with ID3 is thir 4 5 6 okay so
track
the row with ID 1 to the empty table and
drag row with id2 to the empty table
then
ID3 ID
id5
id6 and your automation problem is
solved so this is what we need to
automate if you see here the rows keep
on changing see this is dynamic it's not
like static rows see now you have id1 it
almost like bottom right so this keep on
changing okay so we need to track the
rows in sequence order with ID number
and drop into an empty table so how can
we do that for that let's go back to
trient
tasa so now let us scan the objects okay
right click on the obstacles
select scan and
application now select the application
click on
scan so if you see here this is one
table which is to do tasks and this is
another table which is is completed task
right so we need to drag all the rows
from to-do task
table and we need to drop on completed
task table right so here to do task
table and completed task table these two
we need to select so now these two are
uniquely identified and I'm not seeing
any orange color that means these two
tables are now uniquely identified so
now let us rename this
module with the name of obstacle
copy and paste it here now save the
module let's close the X scan so let's
go back to trient tasa so this is the
new module that we scanned so you have
two tables this is your Source table and
this is your target table so now let us
create a new test case let's go back to
blue color section which is test case
section right click on the folder and
create test case name this with the same
abstral name that we copied earlier
double click on this so now you need to
drag and drop your module onto test case
now let's observe carefully so expand
these all
okay so here if you see I need to
drag the row with the ID number that
starts with one now let's select column
and if you see what is the column that
ID exist the column name is ID so now
what I'm going to do select column Name
ID and
now what is the sell value that I need
to sell
the cell value is one so let me drag my
first row what I'm going to do here I'm
going to specify here simply one okay
the cell value one and here I'm going to
call a method called drag that we used
in earlier lesson drag and change
your action mode as input
okay I'm dragging my first row which
starts with ID 1 and where do I need to
drop I need to drop in this table
completed task table this is my
completed task so I can directly drop
here open curly
braces drop close curly braces and here
your action mode should be
input so let me Simply Save this we have
not completed automating everything okay
I just want to test this one okay right
click and run in
scratchbook it is dragging the row with
ID number
one right done but now how can we drag
rest of all the rows in sequence order
so what we can do here I'm going to
apply a method called
repetition okay how so let me go back to
my test case right click and create a
new folder here what I'm going to do I'm
going to name this as
repetition and I'm going to bring my
entire test case into this repetition
folder I'm just dragging and dropping in
repetition folder now select repetition
folder and expand the properties of
folder okay test case folder if you see
here the repetition how many rows we
have total we have total six rows right
right total six rows what I'm going to
specify here the repetition as six
now instead of
specifying the value one now I want to
delete this I want to use repetition
that we declared here see we declar
repetition here right so simply copy
this and here instead of
one I'm going to use open curly braces
repetition close curly
braces what it does plus first when I
execute your repetition value is 1 right
it comes here here it takes one it drags
the row which has ID 1 and drops here
and this entire folder repeats six time
and second time it again comes here this
time your repetition value is two it
comes down here now the repetition value
we already passed as two it's going to
drag the row with
id2 right and drops in the table like
this it's going to repeat for six times
with 1 2 3 4 5 6 as your value within
the column
cell okay I have selected column as ID
and here I'm repeating the values from 1
to 6 so now let me run this particular
test case and see what happens okay
right click and run in
scratchbook first it's dragged and
dropped number one now dragged and
dropped number
two and then number three
see number
four
five six so you solve this automation
problem so let me just repeat this again
what we did okay so if you see here all
my repetitions are passed so you can see
here repetition one repetition 2
repetition 3 right so here the
repetition value it passed here okay so
let me explain what we did okay first we
have
selected a column as
ID now what is the cell that I want to
select I want to select a cell with ID 1
2 3 4 right those are the Val values in
the cell so those values are coming from
this repetition
folder repetition six times for the
first time it comes as one it drags and
drops for the second time it comes as
two so basically you need to use
repetition folder if you don't use
repetition folder then you have to
repeat the same step six times and then
you need to hard code these values as 1
2 3 4 5 6 so which does not make sense
so you can simply use repetition folder
to repeat six times drag and drop all
the rowes
from Source table to the Target table so
if you have any queries leave your
queries in the comment box I'll try to
respond to your queries thank
you hope you all understand the
obstacle where you need to interact with
web table and you need to drag each and
every Row from web table which are
dynamic in nature and drop onto a new
empty web table by using
repetition drag and drop
methods please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos don't forget to like and
share the video thank you
[Music]